<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Stephanie Z</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Stephanie Z</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://st3p.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smart Materials</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/smartmaterials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/smartmaterials/</guid><description>What are smart materials? A smart material is an object that holds a property that is susceptible to change with the introduction of an external stimulus. This change must be either tangible or visible for the material to qualify for ‘smart’ status. These changes can include:
Electrical Chemical Thermal Mechanical Magnetic The definition of smart materials has been expanded recently to include any materials that may not display a physical change, but do hold electronic functionality.</description></item><item><title>CNC Machines</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/cnc-machines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/cnc-machines/</guid><description>What is a CNC? CNC are manufacturing machines that run on numeric controlled programs to manufacture parts of high precision for the industry. The CNC uses different software&amp;rsquo;s to control all of the machines motions as the spindle speed and the axes movements. This machines uses a special language called “G-Code”.
Before the CNC Machines the manufacture parts were done manually by machinists, they were less precise and took a lot more time than tne CNC the be done.</description></item><item><title>Soap factory</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/monument/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/monument/</guid><description>One of London&amp;rsquo;s lesser-known monuments is this reminder of the London Soap and Cosmetic Company at Clarence and South streets. The factory, here from 1875 to 1984, burned in April 1985, at which time it was the oldest surviving soap factory in Canada. These machines were taken from the ruins and made into a monument by the Ontario Society for Industrial Archaeology.
The monument is located on South St. next to Richard B.</description></item><item><title>battlebots</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/battlebots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/battlebots/</guid><description>how does it work? It is a combat between two remote controlled robots until one is incapacitated. This competitions are televised the most famous ones are robot wars in the UK and BattleBots in the US, they were televised for a short period of time in the 1990 and 2000, with a little hype in the 2010. There are smaller robot combat events that are staged for live audiences such as those organized by the Robot Fighting League.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Stores</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/automatedbussiness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/automatedbussiness/</guid><description>The idea of a robot or android or whatever technological being doing chores for human beings had always been there, in every futuristic movie or carton there is a bot that its main job is to make menial chores. Nowadays it is a reality, it began with little machines that swept and mopped the floor but know it had evolved into whole places that run without human interaction. Shops and fast-food restaurants that ad no longer human employees but robots that manage to do the same work more efficiently, precise, and quick, here are three examples of this places:</description></item><item><title>The coolest industrial robots</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/industrialrobots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/industrialrobots/</guid><description>The industrial robot is a programmable manipulator in three or more axes with various purposes, automatically controlled and re-programmable. The field of industrial robotics can be defined as the study, design and use of robots for the execution of industrial processes.
There are 5 types of robots:
Manipulative robots. Learning or repetition robots. Computer robots. Intelligent (experimental) robots. Micro and nanorobots. 5. FANUC M-2000iA/1700L The strongest 6 axis robot on the market, it comes with a handling capacity up to 2.</description></item><item><title>The Grand Theatre</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/theatre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/theatre/</guid><description>The theatre opened on September 9, 1901 under the ownership of the theatre magnate, Ambrose Small who reportedly considered this theatre his favourite of his numerous similar holdings. He disappeared mysteriously on December 2, 1919. That day, Mr. Small deposited one million dollars in a Toronto bank account, lunched with his wife and was never seen again. Weeks after his disappearance, the night watchman swore he saw Mr. Small entering The Grand Theatre.</description></item><item><title>The new era of wearable technology</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/newtatoos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/newtatoos/</guid><description>DuoSkin This tattoo is able to control and act as a interface with different devices. A collaboration between MIT and Microsoft had developed this tattoo&amp;rsquo;s that are touch-sensitive interface.
Duoskin is the name of the revolutionized idea of a tattoo, this technology is wireless and can communicate with different gadgets. It can be used to track different aspects of the body as temperature, without a doubt this is just the beginning of a new era of wearable technology.</description></item><item><title>Mini R2-D2</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/mini-r2-d2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/mini-r2-d2/</guid><description>Frame Design The design was made taking into account the multiple vents and panels of the robot seen on the films, so in a future it could have space to accommodate little systems for their movement. The measurements took into account to make the frame where taken from the website wwww.astromech.com
Head mechanisim Solidworks design The operation of this mechanism is simple it consist on a motor in the center of the head which gives action to a axial gear that moves smoothly thanks to the help of a lazy Susan that is attached to the from and the base of the head.</description></item><item><title>Recreation of the movement of a creature</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/simulation-dragon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/simulation-dragon/</guid><description>simulation of mechanisms using Solidworks. The Mechanism used to recreate the movement is the slider crank. This Mechanism is one of the most used systems in the mathematical field, it is an arrangement of parts designed to make a rotary straight motion movement as the type of movement that makes a piston engine, so me can define it as one type of four bar linkages which has three revolute joints and one sliding joint.</description></item><item><title>Power Supply</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/powersupply/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/powersupply/</guid><description>material MATERIAL CUANTITY MODEL NUMBER
transformer 1 Central derivative 120V - 24V 2A plug 1 single phase 18 or 20 gauge
cable 1 meter two poles 509 - 010
breadboard 1 1 block two strips A22N - 1000 VTA
breadboard cable 2 meters AWG 22
tip pliers 1 cutting pliers 1
clemas 2 small terminals 2 screws TRT - 02
clemas 2 small terminals 3 screws TRT - 03
diode bridge 1 bridge rectifier KBL-4/200
capacitor 2 ceramic 0.</description></item><item><title>Slider Crank</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/slidercrank/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/slidercrank/</guid><description>Simulation of a slide crank in ADAMS and MATLAB. Slider-cranks are a commonly used type of mechanism translating a rotary movement into a linear one, or the other way around. In this lab session, three slider-crank variations were modelled using ADAMS software. Their movements were simulated and analyzed to find the velocities and position for certain input angles. The obtained results were compared to manual computations using the vector loop equations.</description></item><item><title>Clock with logic gates</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/clock/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/clock/</guid><description>12hrs clock using logic gates The 74LS90 decade counter is a counter that is capable of dividing the frequency each time it is connected with one another, therefore it was used to make it send a signal synchronized with the clock pulse so that the desired account, in addition a 74LS47 decoder was connected for the display outputs.
The logic circuits that were used for the construction of the clock were: 74LS90, counter to decades, to count the seconds and minutes; 74LS47, BCD decoder, to decode the counter outputs to outputs for the 7 segment display; 74LS190, synchronous BCD counter, to generate the sequence of the hours (1 to 12); 74LS73, JK flip-flop, to display if it is AM OR PM; 74LS08, 2-input AND; 74LS00, 2-input NAND; finally, 74LS04, NOT.</description></item><item><title>Elevated 4 link mechanism</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/4link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/4link/</guid><description>In 1819 the world was going through a transition that nowadays we call the industrial revolution, the challenge in this era was to make the machines simpler, change most of the systems for others more simpler and easier, mechanisms for converting rotary into linear motion were the ones that were investigated the most, and the accuracy of the system to development was important for the machines that were going to be applied in.</description></item><item><title>Shift Registrers</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/post/shiftregistrers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/post/shiftregistrers/</guid><description>Screen Saver: Basic Scroll: The Mouse For the first part, it was decided to use six JK flip flops (74LS76) connecting their outputs to the J inputs and the negated outputs to the K inputs, for the first flip flop a two input OR (74LS32) connected to the output of the last flip flop and to a pulse signal, so that, together with the clock signal connected to all the flip flops, a high signal would be passed through all the flip flops and with the outputs in parallel connect them to the display.</description></item></channel></rss>