<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on Stephanie Z</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on Stephanie Z</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://st3p.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cyber security</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/cybersecurity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/cybersecurity/</guid><description>What is cybersecurity? Cybersecurity is the practice of protecting systems, networks, and programs from digital attacks. These cyberattacks are usually aimed at accessing, changing, or destroying sensitive information; extorting money from users; or interrupting normal business processes.
Implementing effective cybersecurity measures is particularly challenging today because there are more devices than people, and attackers are becoming more innovative.
Advancements on cybersecurity Blockchain The digital ledger allows for the secure sharing of information and identity authentication, without the typical risks of exposing data to outsiders.</description></item><item><title>Unhackable Internet</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/internet/</guid><description>An internet based on quantum physics will soon enable inherently secure communication. A team at Delft University of Technology, is building a network connecting four cities in the Netherlands entirely by means of quantum technology. Messages sent over this network will be unhackable.
The Delft network, will be the first to transmit information between cities using quantum techniques from end to end. The technology relies on a quantum behavior of atomic particles called entanglement.</description></item><item><title>Smart Materials</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/smartmaterials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/smartmaterials/</guid><description>What are smart materials? A smart material is an object that holds a property that is susceptible to change with the introduction of an external stimulus. This change must be either tangible or visible for the material to qualify for ‘smart’ status. These changes can include:
Electrical Chemical Thermal Mechanical Magnetic The definition of smart materials has been expanded recently to include any materials that may not display a physical change, but do hold electronic functionality.</description></item><item><title>CNC Machines</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/cnc-machines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/cnc-machines/</guid><description>What is a CNC? CNC are manufacturing machines that run on numeric controlled programs to manufacture parts of high precision for the industry. The CNC uses different software&amp;rsquo;s to control all of the machines motions as the spindle speed and the axes movements. This machines uses a special language called “G-Code”.
Before the CNC Machines the manufacture parts were done manually by machinists, they were less precise and took a lot more time than tne CNC the be done.</description></item><item><title>Soap factory</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/monument/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/monument/</guid><description>One of London&amp;rsquo;s lesser-known monuments is this reminder of the London Soap and Cosmetic Company at Clarence and South streets. The factory, here from 1875 to 1984, burned in April 1985, at which time it was the oldest surviving soap factory in Canada. These machines were taken from the ruins and made into a monument by the Ontario Society for Industrial Archaeology.
The monument is located on South St. next to Richard B.</description></item><item><title>battlebots</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/battlebots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/battlebots/</guid><description>how does it work? It is a combat between two remote controlled robots until one is incapacitated. This competitions are televised the most famous ones are robot wars in the UK and BattleBots in the US, they were televised for a short period of time in the 1990 and 2000, with a little hype in the 2010. There are smaller robot combat events that are staged for live audiences such as those organized by the Robot Fighting League.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Stores</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/automatedbussiness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/automatedbussiness/</guid><description>The idea of a robot or android or whatever technological being doing chores for human beings had always been there, in every futuristic movie or carton there is a bot that its main job is to make menial chores. Nowadays it is a reality, it began with little machines that swept and mopped the floor but know it had evolved into whole places that run without human interaction. Shops and fast-food restaurants that ad no longer human employees but robots that manage to do the same work more efficiently, precise, and quick, here are three examples of this places:</description></item><item><title>The coolest industrial robots</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/industrialrobots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/industrialrobots/</guid><description>The industrial robot is a programmable manipulator in three or more axes with various purposes, automatically controlled and re-programmable. The field of industrial robotics can be defined as the study, design and use of robots for the execution of industrial processes.
There are 5 types of robots:
Manipulative robots. Learning or repetition robots. Computer robots. Intelligent (experimental) robots. Micro and nanorobots. 5. FANUC M-2000iA/1700L The strongest 6 axis robot on the market, it comes with a handling capacity up to 2.</description></item><item><title>The Grand Theatre</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/theatre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/theatre/</guid><description>The theatre opened on September 9, 1901 under the ownership of the theatre magnate, Ambrose Small who reportedly considered this theatre his favourite of his numerous similar holdings. He disappeared mysteriously on December 2, 1919. That day, Mr. Small deposited one million dollars in a Toronto bank account, lunched with his wife and was never seen again. Weeks after his disappearance, the night watchman swore he saw Mr. Small entering The Grand Theatre.</description></item><item><title>The new era of wearable technology</title><link>https://st3p.github.io/articles/newtatoos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://st3p.github.io/articles/newtatoos/</guid><description>DuoSkin This tattoo is able to control and act as a interface with different devices. A collaboration between MIT and Microsoft had developed this tattoo&amp;rsquo;s that are touch-sensitive interface.
Duoskin is the name of the revolutionized idea of a tattoo, this technology is wireless and can communicate with different gadgets. It can be used to track different aspects of the body as temperature, without a doubt this is just the beginning of a new era of wearable technology.</description></item></channel></rss>